[clears throat]
>> I got a lot of homework done today.
>> [snorts]
>> That's long span, wasn't it?
That action. Long dry spell.
How are you Calvin?
Calvin Watkins, Dallas Morning News.
This is for Jerry. Shaddy
made two moves for the defense. Got a
trade for what appears to be a Mike and
then you get a versatile
edge rusher. Can you guys talk about
what you guys did tonight?
I'll I'll start, but I do want to hand
it off to Shaddy get more specific for
what y'all need.
But uh
we have uh been able to
as of right now
um
we
reinstitute or rebuild
this defense.
And um I think the fact that um I have
said it earlier today
the fact that we've
uh put a new newness to the
to the system, a newness to the coaching
staff.
And boy, we're getting some new faces
over there if you count
what we've added this year. And I won't
count that cuz it's a better looking
picture, but still uh
um we've changed this defense and uh
um
if it were just last year the way we
played
on defense
then um that might not have called for
this.
But uh this is a product and what you're
seeing going on right now is a product
of three or four or five years or maybe
more that uh we just haven't been able
to ultimately get where we're trying to
go and be a contender.
Uh and so I personally
just because it's going to be different,
it's going to be fresh, we've got a lot
of great energy here.
We've got guys coming in like the guys
that uh we introduced today.
Uh they can be a part when the defense
does become what we want it to be or
what it could be they did it.
It's their defense. They're not joining.
And we've got a lot of that attitude
around and Shaddy is a uh
a second year coach, he's got that too.
So I'm going to dwell on it.
Uh if we've done anything, just look at
these first picks.
>> [snorts]
>> Then you go back and look at who's
influencing them, which is uh the
staff's influencing them. We're doing
that a lot.
And um so I'd say that in general
when I lay my head down tonight, I'm
going to say we're doing something about
the defense on this team.
Yeah, and what I'd add to that is I
think, you know go back to the moves we
made
last year through the Quinnin, you know,
the Casey, those additions, what we did
in free agency with Jaylon Thompson,
Rashaan Gary,
PJ Locke, you know the guys we added um
we felt like this would be a
continuation of getting the defense
where we want it to be. Uh couldn't be
more thrilled with the addition of D
Winners.
Uh this is a guy we've been watching
play for a while. Uh he's got 17 starts,
rare speed and athleticism. Um adds a a
veteran in that room for us, which is
great. Um and then, you know, I think
you look at what we got with with Jaylon
is a piece that has played both on the
ball at Michigan off the ball at
Michigan, at Maryland. And so we think,
you know, versatility with with him is
going to be something that causes major
problems for people that we play and um
D's athleticism jumps off the tape,
Jaylon's physicality jumps off the tape.
Like if you were doing the old Oklahoma
drill, which my old man would love to
see uh I'd probably put Jaylon out there
uh
uh one of the first reps.
Todd Archer for the ESPN. Will, when did
uh
Barham get on get on your roster? I
think he he's been on our roster, I mean
on on in our view excuse me, our radar
um
kind of all season, especially when we
started talking about what we were
trying to do defensively when at the
combine Christian came in and talked
about the linebackers and the outside
and the inside linebackers and
potentially doing some different things.
Um and then you start looking at Averett
Reese, there's a lot of similarities uh
in in what they do and how they did it
and
um
just excited to get him on the roster
because of the
number one, he's extremely physical. Um
you want to increase the speed of your
defense and the toughness, I think he
does that. And Stephen, on the Winners
uh acquisition
twice now in the last month or so you've
done a deal with the Niners. Are they
easy to do deals with? Yeah, John and I
serve on the competition committee, he's
a dear friend, obviously so much respect
uh for him. What he's done for this
league in this league I think speaks for
itself. He's a
great player
uh in this league and then uh he's done
a great job commentating in this league
and then he's turned around and done a
great job um managing managing his team,
but he and I have a great relationship.
Uh obviously there's some uh
uh you know, we're competing against one
another. We were laughing
uh between two deals with the 49ers and
one with the Eagles, strange bedfellows
if you will.
But uh no, we feel real comfortable with
John and I think he feels comfortable
with us and
uh you know, it just shows you if if you
want something and they want something
then you can make a deal.
John Machota with the Athletic for
Jerry, uh
how'd you keep yourself busy waiting
until pick 92 today?
I'm the world's most active noodler.
>> [clears throat and laughter]
>> I don't even want to look at this
noodling I've done for the last 6 hours,
it might scare me.
>> [laughter]
>> But um
I do want to add one other thing, but I
I I didn't stay busy and we uh actually
we got a chance and should have
as it would have it, we did a lot of
discussing football players while we
were in there, the ones that uh
we looked at in the draft uh uh those
guys sitting around, your top scouts uh
we're all sitting there, we're talking
football, we're talking what makes a
player, all that kind of stuff.
Didn't
didn't waste that great time together.
And uh
um uh that's important for us all to uh
get on the same page. I do want to add
that. We've got uh who else we got on
our staff San Francisco other than our
special teams coach who didn't know this
knew our player well after And Nick was
the main one. Nick Nick was around him
more than I knew the fact. One of the
things that you get now when you when
you do bring in some new coaches
is you get a familiarity obvious obvious
with where they've been coaching.
And um
uh certainly uh uh they get to know them
pretty well when they've coached some of
your uh
And then for Stephen, uh you guys have
to be patient waiting till that pick and
now you have three picks in the fourth
round. Uh just what do you think about
what's left out there for you guys then
having those three fourth round picks?
Oh, I think it's outstanding. I think
Will's said it, I'm repeating Will, but
uh meat of this draft was in the fourth
and fifth round. And uh
you know, we were
able to pull the best player off our our
board in Barham, but we think we're
going to have a great opportunity. You
know, we strategically if you ask for
it, you want to have
you know, a couple picks high, which we
do, uh to have all night to think about
it. Who's the right guy for us, who's
the right fit?
And to be up there picking in the you
know, top 12 if you will.
Uh you know, I think it's huge uh to be
able to really think about what we want
to come away with there. I think they're
very important and that's why why we
really didn't want to package those uh
uh to move up and we were really never
enticed to do it and so uh
you know, I think we're going to get
three really good football players uh
based on all the work we've done on the
board. Uh I think we're going to get,
you know, guys we have third and fourth
round grades on uh for those picks and
that's only going to help our football
team. We did a list of all the fourth
round players that we've had here Murray
and just just go down to them. Dak was
our second pick the fourth round. Uh and
there's a nice little list of by the way
while we had time to talk waiting on the
deal to go by the day, so we just
started listing our fourth rounders of
the past.
Nick Harris, Fort Worth Star-Telegram.
When did the uh talks with San Francisco
begin? Was it something that was on your
radar going into the weekend and then
how did it develop in the moment as
well? That goes all the way back.
First time we broached it was when we
traded Osa uh to them.
And uh so
we've kind of had that on our radar,
they've kind of had it on theirs. It's
just taken some time to uh
you know, for it to come around.
Sometimes you have to be patient on
these things and
I know they were
uh working on their end being patient
and uh but no, we uh had D on our radar
for
what, 6 weeks, 8 weeks? I mean, it's
been a while. So
you know, he was one of the guys that we
had, you know, especially when we missed
out in free agency.
Uh you know, that we had on our radar uh
that could really step up and and and be
that guy who could really jump in, fill
in. It's great uh we got a hold of him
tonight. Uh he was over in Arlington, I
think, moving into a new house. So uh
uh it's got to feel good for him. He
loves uh no state taxes, all those
things are good.
>> [laughter]
>> As of now, do you all see him as the
green dot?
>> [snorts]
>> Yeah, well we're going to let them all
train, you know, and we don't have to
make that decision today. Uh we just
feel great about the guys we've added
and
um our thing Nick is during the spring
and and training camp they're all going
to have the green dot and we're going to
let guys take turns doing it and see who
does it the best.
Tom. Tommy DallasCowboys.com. But for
Bryan, you mentioned Jay Shawn playing
inside and outside at Michigan. When you
watch it, do you feel like there's one
spot he's he's maybe better at him that
you want him at here versus another?
We're going to try him at inside
linebacker first. We love the
physicality that he plays with, but
again, one of the things that if you
watch a Christian Parker led defense,
Vic Fangio, it's all guys that can play
off the ball, but then they stem on the
ball. Think of Zach Born. You know, guys
that have the ability to do that. They
change it change our line calls
offensively.
But we think that we want we want to
start him inside, but we also know that
we can move him as a rusher on third
down
passing situations and that's what we
love about the guy. And then for the
panel with winners in 2023, what do you
recall about him going through the
pre-draft process and your evaluations
of him? And you've mentioned in the past
we acquire players that you usually
stick with those in case you get them
down the line. What do you remember
about him coming out? Yeah, just going
through the process and looking at him
coming out of TCU. He's athletic, he's
fast, he loved football
and and
could go play in space. And so those are
all things and now you see him play at
the NFL level and you see those things
grow and him get better at those. So I
we followed him all throughout because
he had traits that we liked and then the
character part and the things about
loving football was there. So we keep
our eye on him.
Go. Uh Joe White, Dallas Morning News.
Uh Stephen, the trade for DeMarvion
Overshown shortly after a few
linebackers went in that second round.
Was there any hope that maybe one of
these guys would fall and then when it
didn't happen, maybe that was the signal
to make the deal or or how did that kind
of go? Yeah, I mean you have to be
realistic. That trade was uh you know,
in the works for a while and
you know, we were pretty realistic that
we were probably weren't going to get a
shot at any one of those three guys that
went.
You know, for that matter, we we were
big fans of another one that went in the
second as well. So uh
you know, you got to be realistic and we
had started working on this again,
really re-upped it actually before the
draft even started. We had
kind of started discussions on it. So
just so happened they had their hands
full with the first pick in the second
round and
we
finally got every on the page with
everything there uh
shortly thereafter after they made their
selection and
ready to move forward. And Bryan, all
three picks have been 30 visit guys. You
know, teams use 30 visit in a variety of
different ways. How important is the 30
visits for these three guys so far in
the draft and for you guys?
>> Yeah, well, I think, you know, I take a
lot of pride in the way we do it. I
think we do it
as good as anybody in the league. We get
them here, they get a chance to meet
with
you know,
from ownership down to Will and his
guys, the coaches
um
and so I feel like we get a a very
comprehensive
um evaluation of them and not just their
football learning, but what they're
about, their
their understanding of fitting into a
team culture and putting the team above
themselves and
uh we always find ways to compete. So
I think it's that we do it really well.
We find the right guys to bring in and
it's a little easier to sign off when
you know what you're buying, especially
when you see the talent on film, but you
also know the type of person that you're
bringing into that locker room.
Tom.
Todd Archer, the Athletic. Jerry
Stephen, you guys talked about how you
guys don't really want to do a lot of
redshirt players this year, but when
there's a player at this point going
into day three of the draft where, you
know, might have some medical question
marks, specifically maybe at cornerback,
at what point is that kind of a gamble
that you're willing to take at this
point as opposed to the earlier rounds?
Go ahead. Uh we um
uh
we think we're going to
get players in the fourth round.
I'm trying to be real specific. Uh yeah,
we think about redshirting them and this
is the place to do it, not in the second
where I've done it before and
drew back a nub. It didn't work.
Um
but uh
uh if you can get a guy that should be a
for select in the first round, you can
get him in the second a lot of times,
but uh
he um he can disappoint because of the
availability. Uh but four
uh if the right thing right situation is
there, the right prognosis
uh and by the way, uh for
a good one to be there, then it's
probably uh
uh only the man up there really knows
how it's going to turn out. And so uh
uh uh
I can say this, you won't see us do this
uh
uh not in the fourth round.
Tomorrow.
We've got a these guys
we think there's enough players right
there that they can be on the 53 and be
helping us beat Giants.
And Will, you guys have gone to the
defensive line Michigan a few times in
recent drafts.
Obviously, coaching staffs change and
all that all that kind of stuff. Is
there any things that are consistent in
terms of how you evaluate those players
or is it a completely new process each
time? Well, we evaluate all the players
the same in whatever we do. We don't
change the process based on where we go
to school or anything like that. We look
for the same the same markers, the same
things. We ask the same people the same
questions. I think universities, they
kind of change, okay, people change and
so we get the opportunity. Maybe the
information's a little bit different,
but we go do the work the same way every
time we go in any player.
Patrick.
Hey fellas, Patrick Walker,
DallasCowboys.com. To Will, you talked a
lot in the pre-draft process about
marrying what the scouting department
does and the traits you guys are looking
for with Christian Parker's wants
for the defense.
Versatility seems to be a massive thing
for what he's looking for. Can you talk
about just the concerted effort from
both free agency acquisitions, guys like
Jaylon Thompson and PJ Locke to Caleb
Downs being the 11th overall pick and
just how concerted effort that has been
for you guys to make sure that you get
versatile guys? At the end of the day,
the more quality football players that
you have that can do multiple things,
the more multiple you can be.
You know, that's from a strategy
standpoint, from a coaching standpoint,
but and then the more players that you
have, you know, injuries happen. There's
17 weeks and things happen. You have to
have people that can fill in people that
you trust. And if you get good football
players that have versatility, you have
an opportunity to do that. And their
brain has to work to be able to
understand what you're doing, how you're
doing it and I think the training and
coaching and all that stuff goes into
it. But that's a big big part of it. And
so from a coaching standpoint, that's a
great point that Will makes to the
football IQ, the brain has to be there.
What does that do for your culture in
the locker room and what does it do for
your defense on as a whole knowing that
you have so many guys who can play so
many positions at a high level? Yeah, I
think that's what you're looking for.
That's what, you know, from the
offensive side of it as I look at it,
Patrick, it's what makes it hard on us.
You know, when you've got pieces out
there, you're not sure exactly where
they're going to align, where they're
going to play. They can do different
things. You know, the way you really
teach anymore in in phase two, when you
get on the grass is it's concept
teaching. You're teaching guys how to
you're the quarter hook dropper or hey,
you're you've got speed at three, so
you're the danger player that's got to
overlap and
um you know, it's it's invaluable
because, you know,
everything that we do is based off of,
okay, hey, they're in nickel 4-2, nickel
3-3, nickel 5-1
because they have tendencies that you're
anticipating. So when you're calling a
play on offense, the first thing you
listen to is what personnel they're in
and then your mind starts to kind of
work a little bit. Occasionally, you'll
even adjust the call based on what
personnel they're in and if we can build
certain five down fronts from five down
people, but four down as well and put
one of these guys on the edge, then
we're going to do that.
Garrett. Garrett Podell, CBS Sports.
Bryan, at what point do you and Clayton
Adams on day three of the draft start
saying, "Hey, are we going to go offense
at all?" Uh Clayton's been great, man.
Clayton he's there
for the drinks post-draft and uh he
again, he understands that George
Pickens was a third pick in this draft,
third round pick for us. But no,
Clayton's a great team player and
you know, we
we we addressed two really big needs for
for us in free agency with Javonte and
and George and
we're excited about some of the young
guys that we get to develop. And
I'm not saying we're not going to go
offense, defense or even special teams.
We're going to take the best player
available that's going to help us win
and compete for a championship next
year. when that process is happening,
you're like, "Well, actually, I prefer
the guys we have on the roster." Well,
again, I I I don't think it's it's that.
I think it's guys that maybe have the
traits that we expect when we do our job
as a coaching staff, we get the most out
of a Jayden Blue, a Tyler Guyton.
Um
you know, Cooper Beebe is still a young
player. There's guys on defense, same
thing, you know, Vaughn, you know,
Caelen Carson. You know, there's guys
like that that we're excited to see
Shamari James.
You know, coaches are evaluated on wins
first, but then it's secondly, they're
evaluated on their ability to develop
players. And that's what we have to do
cuz we've got some very talented young
players. We've also added to the
competition. When you add competition,
it makes everybody better because they
see, "Damn, that guy's really talented."
And so
I'm really excited about this coaching
staff we've put together and
again, we're going to have a great day
tomorrow. I've had defensive
coordinators
when the head coach was an offensive
coordinator
when the defensive coordinator was no
longer with the Cowboys, say one of the
problems we had
is the coach needs to be more the head
coach and let less the coordinator
and I could get more guys active and we
could
have a little more uh
impartial look when we're taking
players.
Mike
and I've got to say reason I'm down
going down this road and
Brian
are as outstanding as I've been around
of being the head coach when it comes to
personnel rather than letting the
offensive coordinator in them
look at
the issue when we've got either or and
it's always either or it's always either
or.
And
Brian's excellent.
And that's got to have come from his
varied background how he grew up but
he's excellent now.
And he'll sit up there and he can be as
cold and as
factual and as flatline
about what's best for the whole team.
And although obviously he's uh
at the end of the day uh
got to move that ball have a job.
>> [laughter]
>> All offense tomorrow guys.
Not.
Stephen knowing you like the whole 365
24/7 on the player acquisition where
would you say you are at linebacker do
you feel like you've gotten where you
want to be or is there a little more
work to be done this off season? I think
there's work to be done. We're still
building the room.
You know we needed to rebuild it.
As Chris said I think we only have two
chairs in the room before the draft so
No we we need to keep
being a creative there and adding
players and
have competition and so we'll uh
certainly give that a good going over
you know as we look at situations
tomorrow but uh
I do think it's a work in progress and
uh
certainly it was a big step getting
Damien he started two years on a damn
good defense for the 49ers.
And he played at a high level and
obviously a huge get for us in terms of
NFL experience but uh we do want to keep
building the room and you know the guy
we took today he's he's versatile. I
mean that's the most important thing. I
mean he's
he's played behind the line at Michigan
and he's not unlike Micah and he's
played rushing the passer so
that was very enticing to us. I don't
know who said it but versatility is
important in this defense that you're
able to
do a lot of things and then of course
all these guys are going to help Nick
out in special teams and
those type of things so
yeah I think it's a work in progress.
We're certainly not going to stand pat.
We got other linebackers to get and
we'll see uh
see how it works out tomorrow. If we
don't get it tomorrow then as you said
we continue player acquisition
throughout the throughout the year.
Brian if it is all offense all day
tomorrow
is there
a part of that offense that you might
like to see something happen in to
address or do you feel like it's it
could be
any help there would be fine? No yeah at
the end of the day I love our process
you know Skyler I really do. I think you
know we have great debates as we're
approaching the clock and you know
Jerry's great Stephen they like to hear
all the different options and the
players that we're interested in and why
and there's great conversation back and
forth so I think you know the best thing
I've learned from being around these
guys now in my second year in this chair
is the process works. The hours that go
into it sets the table for us to have
success and to select the right player
for us but as we approach being on the
clock the the conversations are so
powerful because we
usually come to a agreement that this is
the best thing for the Dallas Cowboys.
Jonah
Jonah Deibler WFAA
Someone asked my question a little bit
earlier so I'll give you a softball. How
do you guys stay wired as these drafts
go on
and the players become maybe a little
less
notable to the general public. How do
you stay engaged as each pick kind of
goes on? It's what we do for a living
right? I mean we're trying to bring a
championship we're trying to win. My
guys we're trying to find players to
build a championship right? And and we
haven't done that and so there's a drive
to continue to get better and do that.
That's what drives us to go do it and if
you can find one in the fourth fifth
sixth seventh round free agent that does
something for you then now you're adding
more value to your team because you you
know your return on investment. So
that's what we're trying to do is always
get better.
>> I guess my question is do you have an
espresso machine in the war room?
>> No.
No it's it's watching tape talking to
the crew. It's it's just we love what we
do. I don't need any caffeine.
Since you asked us all the question
it's the old miner
that's done it all of his life broken
down been over. He's been hitting that
pick to hit that gold
and he doesn't hit one time
walks away
and a fresh guy walks up here young guy
just bam and there's the gold mine.
The facts are that if you hit that thing
enough
you get to do it and so uh
you you just got to go back and do it
and do it and
it's I've seen it happen. I've seen us
pick great players in the fourth round
Murray people like that.
And I've seen us get some great free
agents Romo.
I mean I'm not obviously I'm pointing
out the good. The fact that you can get
one
or the fact that you've had one that
might have
possibly been mine because of injury yet
he's come back and who was our great
guard that we had over in Memphis that
we had him so far back. Ron Leary Ron
Leary and turned out to play for 10
years. It's the same injury he had the
reason he wasn't drafted.
We went over had a plane go over and get
Leary.
Lyle Lyle
because he couldn't get drafted and uh
we got him over here the next morning
and and signed him and he was all all
I'm saying is
we're in something here that because it
can happen one time doesn't mean it can
happen again. Now do you make livings on
going against those kinds of odds? No.
You couldn't make a living on the odds
of getting downs like we got him last
night and followed down there too. You
count on all that stuff every day and
you really
won't go there. That's a dreamer almost.
But the idea that
we we we've got to walk in that room
right as everybody else did and look at
these players
and we've got draft picks and we've got
some great coaches and why not? We can
put it together two teams in the Super
Bowl.
They didn't make the playoffs here
before.
So my point is
that really is uh
I'm 84 years old.
And man
I know it can happen.
Cuz I've I've done it when it didn't
work I've done it when it worked. You
just keep hitting that pick.
Will your staff have done a really good
job on day three. How much pride do
y'all put in these day three guys and
UDFAs and specifically this year's
process how confident are you on it?
Yeah it's a big big part of it and and
you know you have to see the talent
that's there the talent that's available
and you have to identify what fits you
especially when it comes down to the
free agent process and then you've got
to be
you know these guys go do the work. They
know who the guys are better than all of
us. This is their time to dig those guys
out and so it's the belief in the
process and the belief in them that
gives us the opportunity to find those
guys. I think one of the great things
that Shady does is challenges our scouts
and and their opinion on things and so
if you love your job and you want to
contribute you feel that desire to be
right and so this is these guys time to
shine and see if they can add something
to the roster and everybody takes great
pride in it. You don't have to say who
they are but you kind of go into day
three every year being like man I'd love
to get that guy if he's there like a pet
cat that you have during the process? It
goes based on our board. I mean we value
guys the right way we know what we like
and then you know there's there's always
guys that that we call them our pet cats
and some guys don't like to say they
call them their pet god those or
whatever but everybody has their guy
that they like and then
we we we
go to the carpet about why do you like
him and then finding those things out
and the opportunity comes to get him
you know we'll see if we can do it.
And I'd say it's punitive to go against
the board. You get glared at.
>> [laughter]
>> No it is and and that isn't anything
doesn't make any difference who's
writing the paycheck either. You can get
there's a there's a system in place and
when that thing is broken you better be
ready to explain it.
And
explain it to each other. Real debate.
We had a hell of a debate in there
yesterday morning before the draft.
Yesterday morning on something that was
very material right there.
And we were going at it and
I could I had to let up. I could see
Will getting red.
He's getting hot. He got he's getting
hot. [laughter]
Do you ever try and stir it up on
purpose? Jerry do you ever try and stir
it up on purpose? Really?
>> [laughter]
>> That's what I do. That's what I do and
you know it.
All right everybody thank Thank you
guys. Watch that cord. Watch the
cord. Watch the whole watch.
Oh
As long as it's not mine.
>> [laughter]
>> Hey John leave it I got it. You got it.
Yeah we got it. Okay thank you. There
you go. Thank you all.
>> Yeah.
Amen.